sma.ie 2009-01-23

# Society of African Missions - Privacy Policy

\- 

**Society of African Missions **

**Privacy Policy**

Thank you for visiting The Society of African Mission's website and reviewing our privacy policy. This policy applies only to information collected via our offical website. 

The Society of African Missions [Irish Province], Place of Registration Cork, Ireland is committed to protecting the privacy of our members and supporters. The following SMA Privacy Policy will explain to you how we collect, store and use personal information submitted to us. 

We value and respect all individuals and organisations seeking to donate time, money or resources to our work with the poorest of the poor in the developing world. We endeavour to protect our usersâ€™ information, through compliance with The Data Protection Act 1988. When our supporters submit personal and sensitive information this information is protected by a secure system both online and offline. 

When you contact the Society of African Missions regarding an event, activity, campaign, send or receive information or make a donation, you can provide us with your personal information. The personal data provided is stored on our secure computerised database to enable us to respond to your requests, keep you updated and informed about our work and how your donation(s) is being used. We may communicate with you in the future by mail, email and telephone. 

Personal information (such as name, address, telephone number, email address) is protected by the Society of African Missions on a computerised system to ensure that loss, misuse, unauthorised access or disclosure, alteration or destruction of this information is not probable. 

Sensitive information (such as credit card number, account number, online donations) is protected by a secure server software provided by industry leader Realex. This secure software encrypts financial information provided online. It prevents anyone else reading your personal and sensitive information while your donation is being processed online. Like any tax-deductible charitable contribution, any on-line contribution made to the Society of African Missions [Irish Province] cannot be cancelled or returned online once it has been completed. For details in this regard contact Fr Tom Curran SMA., Communications Director, Society of African Missions, Blackrock Rd., Cork. 

To ensure we have an accurate personal record of our supporters, please contact us if your personal details have changed so we can update your record. 

Our web site is managed professionally and uses cookies - information that is sent by Society of African Missions to your computer when you log onto our web site â€“ we use the information collected to help us understand more about how our web site is used by our supporters and how we could improve our web site to better suit your needs. 

If you have any queries or questions about privacy and/or security of your personal data please contact us at [tom.curran@sma.ie](mailto:tom.curran@sma.ie) or visit [www.dataprotection.ie](http://www.dataprotection.ie/) for further information. 

Acceptance of Terms/Changes to Privacy Policy: Your use of the SMA web site indicates an acceptance of the terms of the Society of African Missions Privacy Policy. The Society of African Missions reserves the right to update or amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Such changes will be posted on this page without prior notification. 

**Fr Tom Curran SMA., Communication Director  
1st February 2007**  

* * *

**Page created** : Sunday, December 7th, 2003

**Last modified** : Wednesday, February 14th, 2007
